别这样。星期六。
他们在楼下看动画片
come on. It's Saturday.
They're downstairs watching cartoons.
- 他们要是上来怎么办？
- 不不，他们正看得欢呢
- But what if they come up.
- No no, they're in the zone, okay?
只要有电咱们就是安全的
We're safe as Iong
as there's eIectricity.
什么，就这样了？
完事了？
What, is that it?
Are we done?
有东西撞墙了
Something hit the waII.
- 天，你把我便便都吓出来了！
- 搞什么――
- Jeez, you scared the crap out of me!
- What the--
你搞什么呢？！
what the heII
are you doing?!
我在给你刷墙呢。
你看像什么？
I'm painting your house.
What's it Iook Iike?
看着像……我们安了
世上最丑的百叶窗
Looks Iike... we have the worId's
ugIiest shutters.
听着
Listen.
弗兰克，我们打算雇人刷的
Frank, we were going
to hire painters to do that.
那么，你可以待会再谢我
So, you can
thank me Iater.
我喜欢好吃的巧克力
I Iike fine chocoIates.
爸，求你了，
快下来，好吗？
Dad, pIease,
get down from there, okay?
我们在――我们想――
睡觉呢
We're-- we're trying to...
sIeep here.
哦，当然，是的。
逮到你们了
Oh, sure, yeah.
I got you.
星期六的小睡后清醒剂？
A IittIe Saturday morning
wake me up?
关上窗户，我不会听的
Just cIose the window.
I won't Iisten.
你知道，我担心的不是听
You know, I'm not worried
about the Iistening.
而是窃听
It's the heckIing.
妈，爸怎么
在刷我们的房子？
Ma, why is Dad
painting the house?
哦，这是我给你的礼物
Oh, that's my gift to you.
什么？！
What?!
你们总说起要刷房子……
You two aIways taIk
about having your house painted...
所以，我把这活交给你爸了
so, I put your father
on the job.
可是，玛丽，
我们打算雇专业人员的
But, Marie, we were going
to hire professionaIs.
哦，可是弗兰克做得很好
Oh, but Frank
is very good.
我们的房子上
他就做得很好
He did a nice job
on our house...
并且他喜欢漆味
and he Iikes the fumes.
唔，是的，你们的房子
他是刷得不错，并且……
WeII, yes, he did do a nice job
on your house and...
我也讨厌给人泼冷水，
可是――
I wouId hate to kiII
anyone's buzz, but--
是的，可我们在想，
Yeah, but we were kind of thinking
这种事应该我们做主，
that we wouId be the ones
to make that decision,
因为这也算是我们的房子
'cause it is
kind of our house.
是，可我们才是得看着它的
Yes, but we're the ones
who have to Iook at it.
好吧，我拿法国吐司
骗他下来
AII right, I'm going to use this
french toast to Iure him off the Iadder.
好吧好吧好吧。
就让你爸做吧
Okay okay okay.
Just Iet your father do this.
我需要他离开我的房子
I need him
out of my house.
自从他退休，
他老是在我眼前晃
Ever since he's retired,
he's around aII the time.
是啊，可退了休
就是这样
Yeah, but that's what happens
when you retire.
我知道，我只是没想到
他会活这么长
I know, but I never thought
he'd Iive this Iong.
行了，妈，看
Come on, Ma, Iook.
那不是我们的错，好吗？
That's not our probIem,
aII right?
你有40年时间下毒
You've had 40 years
to poison him.
好吧。好吧。
雷蒙德，求你了……
Okay. Fine.
Raymond, pIease...
我需要空间。
我需要自己的时间
I need space.
I need a IittIe time to myseIf.
我想做事的时候
不希望看到他
I don't want him around
when I'm trying to do things.
- 做什么事？
- 当我想要提升自己的时候
- Do what things?
- When I'm trying to improve myseIf.
这可不是一日之功
This doesn't just happen.
我练习外语、唱歌剧，
I practice my Ianguages,
I have my opera,
最近我又开始练瑜伽了
and I'm starting yoga.
你――
You--
怎么了？
这很奇怪吗？
What?
Is that so strange?
- 是的
- 嘿
- Yes.
- Hey.
- 你做什么？
- 刷你的房子
- What are you doing?
- Painting your house.
哦，拜托！
你也来？
Oh, come on!
You too?
妈说我们要的
Ma said we had to.
那么，妈说什么你都做了？
So, you do everything
Ma teIIs you?
现在叛逆可有点迟了，雷蒙德
It's a IittIe Iate
for rebeIIion, Raymond.
行了，看。
我不需要你们俩
Come on, Iook.
I don't need both you guys
吊死在我房子上，好吗？
hanging off my house, okay?
所以回你的卡车，
摇个铃，卖雪糕去吧
So go back in your truck,
ring a beII and seII some fudge pops.
好的，等等。
等等等等等一下，雷
AII right, wait.
Wait wait wait wait a minute, Ray.
你知道，你们来帮忙
真是太热心了
You know, that was
very sweet of you to heIp.
非常感谢，罗伯特
Thanks a Iot, Robert.
- 什――现在你又想他干了？
- 唔，我的意思是，
- Wha-- now you want him to?
- WeII, I mean,
罗伯特愿意来，你爸已经
上手刮旧漆了，所以我说好吧
Robert's offered, your dad's
aIready started scraping, so I say fine.
- 唔，行了，你不想他们――
- 嘿嘿嘿，
- WeII, come on, you don't want them--
- Hey hey hey,
我叫你处理这个
有好几个月了
I've been asking you
to get on this for months.
好吧，好吧，去吧！
AII right, fine, go!
你们想刷房子？
去吧。刷房子吧
You want to paint the house?
Go. Paint the house.
你知道吗？
也许你们三个可以一块刷？
You know what? Maybe aII three of you
can paint it together?
- 这不是很温馨吗？
- 不
- WouIdn't that be nice?
- No.
不，看，今天星期六
No, Iook,
it's Saturday,
我星期六有很多计划，好吗？
and I got a Iot of Saturday things
pIanned, okay?
嘿，兔八哥！
嘿！
Hey, Bugs Bunny!
Hey!
哦，这是什么？
Oh, what is this?
猎鸭季节还是猎兔季节？
Duck season/rabbit season?
哦，小心，小心了
Oh, Iook out, Iook out.
雷蒙德？
Raymond?
- 雷蒙德？
- 什么？
- Raymond?
- What?
这么说你能安心
让他们刷你的房子？
So you're fine with them
painting your house?
星期六
It's Saturday.
好啦！对不起，孩子们
AII right!
Sorry, kids.
看来爸爸不能再和你们享受
大好时光了
Guess Daddy isn't going to be abIe
to spend any more quaIity time with you.
嘿，你怎么样了？
Hey, what do you got?
终于有卖你这么大个的冰棍了
They're finaIIy making
PopsicIes in your size?
你有完没完？
WouId you stop?
我没法忍受这老头了。
他要把我逼疯了
I can't take the oId man anymore.
He's driving me nuts.
来回支使得我像只猴子
Ordering me around
Iike a monkey.
书上有的词
都成我的绰号了
CaIIing me
every name in the book--
娘娘腔、粉扑、
公主……猴子
Nancy, powder puff,
princess... monkey.
那又怎么样？
他叫我蠢蛋、
So? I'm getting dopey,
白痴、傻货
idiot, moron.
至少你的还说得通
At Ieast yours
make sense.
- 唔，祝你好运
- 哦，不。不不不！
- WeII, best of Iuck.
- Oh no. No no no!
拜托，你不能把我
一个人留下跟他！
Come on, you're not
Ieaving me here with him!
你知道跟爸干活
会是什么样子
You knew what it was
going to be Iike working with Dad.
他也有短处让我抓住，雷蒙德
I had him too, Raymond.
他在楼梯上
He was up on the Iadder.
看着会像事故
WouId have Iooked
Iike an accident.
嘿！闲站着干什么？
Hey! What's with aII this
standing around?!
你们给政府干活呢？
You two working
for the government?!
不是！
No!
唔，我不喜欢打断
营火女生（一家组织野营的公司）
的会议
WeII, I hate to break up this meeting
of the Camp Fire GirIs,
不过咱们还是干活吧！
but Iet's get to work!
赶紧了！
Chop! Chop!
- 我们在干活，爸
- 哦是吗？
- We're working, Dad.
- Oh yeah?
漏堵上了吗（招摇够了吗），
查泰莱夫人？
Are you finished cauIking,
Lady ChatterIey?
这句不错
That is a good one.
你为什么不堵上？！
Why aren't you done
cauIking?!
排雨管边上有马蜂窝
There's a wasps' nest
by the down spout.
那就拿棍子捅下来
So, you take a stick
and knock it down.
那是马蜂，
它们不会喜欢的
They're wasps.
They don't Iike that.
哦，那就这么办……
Oh, weII here's
what you do...
要是它们赶你，
if they come at you,
把裙子掀起来遮住头
然后跑
you puII your skirt
over your head and run.
好吧
AII right.
嘿，爸。他不用赌那个排雨管。
没什么重要的
Hey, Dad. He doesn't have to cauIk by
the down spout. It's not that important.
我说重要就重要
It's important
if I say it's important.
好吧，可这是我的房子
Okay, but this is my house.
这是我的活！
This is my job!
人家看见我在这干活
PeopIe see me
working out here.
他们会知道是弗兰克・巴伦
干的活
They're going to know
that Frank Barone did this job,
所以必须干好了！
so it's going
to get done right!
你怎么还在这？
Why are you stiII here?
我――我不认为――
I-- I don't think--
嘿，嘿，只是些虫子
Hey, hey, it's just
a coupIe of bugs.
拿东西捅下来――
Knock it down
with something--
棍子、笤帚！
A stick, a broom!
你的小指头！
我不管！
Your pinky!
I don't care!
上去把那个窝捅下来！
Get up there
and knock out that nest!
好吧！
AII right!
你又在干嘛？
你是刮漆还是要跳舞？
And what about you? Are you going
to scrape that paint or do a dance?
我刮着呢
I'm scraping.
喔啊，等等，爸
Whoa, wait a minute, Dad.
颜色不对。戴比拉想要白色的
You got the wrong coIor.
Debra wanted white.
这很接近了
This is cIose.
这不接近，
这是黄色的
It's not cIose,
it's yeIIow.
她要白色的。
她说了山提利（巴黎北部小村，
以瓷器、蕾丝驰名）蕾丝
She wants white.
She said ChantiIIy Lace.
唔，这是柠檬奶油
WeII this is
Lemon Meringue.
唔，你干嘛买黄色的？
WeII, why did you
get yeIIow?
因为黄色更好
Because yeIIow is better.
是，可黛比拉喜欢白色
Yeah, but Debra Iikes white.
唔，我不管黛比拉喜欢什么，
我也不管你喜欢什么！
WeII I don't care what Debra Iikes,
and I don't care what you Iike!
买了黄色了，好吧？！
It's yeIIow, okay?!
咱们就刷黄色的！
And we're doing it yeIIow!
啊！水管！
Ah! Hose!
拿水管来！
Get the hose!
大宝宝
Big baby.
听着，爸，我得告诉你
Listen, Dad,
I got to teII you.
不只是黛比拉，好吗？
我也喜欢山提利蕾丝
It's not onIy Debra, okay?
I want ChantiIIy Lace too.
爸，你听到我说的了吗？
Dad, do you hear
what I'm saying?!
别把我房子刷黄了。爸！
Don't paint
my house yeIIow. Dad!
别开那个罐子！
Don't you open
that paint can!
爸，你没听我的话
Dad, you're not
Iistening to me.
爸，不要搅那个漆
Dad, don't you
stir that paint.
你要是搅那个漆――
If you stir that paint--
好了，现在你得退
搅过的漆了
Okay, you're just going
to have to return stirred paint now.
因为你开了罐子，
And now that the can's open,
你只能付钱了，好吗？
you're going to have
to pay for it, okay?
因为我是绝对不会付
柠檬奶油的钱的。听到了吗？
'Cause I'm sure as heII not paying
for no Lemon Meringue. You hear me?
我是――哦，你不能！
I'm-- oh no you don't!
不许你过去！
Don't you go near that!
你听到了，爸？
不许――不许你蘸刷子！
You hear me, Dad?!
Don't you-- don't you dip that brush!
你不能蘸刷子
You do not dip
that brush.
我警告你，爸，不要――
I'm warning you.
Dad, don't--
哦，爸，要是我看到你
用那把刷子刷，
Oh, Dad, if I see paint
on that brush,
好了，那是黄的
Okay, that's yeIIow.
那是黄的。爸，
不许把我房子刷成黄的！
That's yeIIow. Dad, don't you paint
my house yeIIow!
你听到没，爸？！
Do you hear me, Dad?!
爸，我警告你！
Dad, I'm warning you!
- 好了，好吧。到此为止
- 嘿！
- Okay, aII right. That's it.
- Hey!
- 到此为止，回家去
- 什么？！
- That's it, go home.
- Excuse me?!
看，如果你不照我想的做，
Look, if you're not going
to do what I want,
- 那就回家去
- 你不能告诉我怎么做
- then go home.
- You don't teII me what to do.
我能只要这是我的房子！
这是我房子，我是老板，好吗？
I do when it's my house! And it's my house
and I'm the boss, okay?
- 所以你被解雇了
- 我被解雇了？！
- So you're fired.
- I'm fired?!
好了，我好了
Okay, I'm aII right now.
嘿，听听这个，罗伯特。
雷蒙德说我被解雇了！
Hey, get a Ioad of this, Robert.
Raymond says I'm fired!
没错，你被解雇了！
That's right, you're fired!
你炒了他？
You fired him?
想炒了我吗？
You want to fire me?
- 你不能解雇我！
- 看，爸，
- You can't fire me!
- Look, Dad,
我不是小孩子了，好吗？
我不喜欢你对我的方式，
I'm not a kid anymore, okay?
I don't Iike the way you treat me
我也不喜欢你对待助手的方式，
所以，到此为止
and I don't Iike the way
you treat the heIp either, so that's it.
好吧！
Fine!
刷你自己的破房子吧
Paint your own damn house.
- 喔
- 没错
- Wow.
- That's right.
现在这归我管了
Now I'm in charge of this now.
好了，咱们要做的第一件事……
Okay, and the first thing
we're going to do...
午饭
Iunch.
- 好的，可现在才9：30
- 午饭！
- Yeah, but it's onIy 9:30--
- Lunch!
嘿，你不能这么进来，
你水嗒嗒的
Hey, you can't come in
Iike that, you're soaking wet.
我还在想这有多好，
巴伦家所有男人一块干活
Here I thought it'd be so nice,
aII the Barone men working together.
没人能和爸一起干活，
你替他干活
No one works with Dad,
you work for him.
因为没人能做得对，除了他
'Cause nobody can do
anything right except him.
- 是的，还记得那个堡垒吗？
- 没错
- Yeah, remember the fort?
- That's right.
罗伯特和我在我们家后院
修了个堡垒――
Robert and I were buiIding a fort
in our backyard--
没什么特别的，
就是个小堡垒
nothing fancy,
just this IittIe fort.
是的，一个能让我们看漫画书和……
Yeah, just a pIace we couId read
our comic books and...
其他杂志的地方
other periodicaIs.
呃呵！
Ugh!
咱们那时候多开心哪，
自己修堡垒，是吧？
And we were having fun too, buiIding
the fort aII by ourseIves, right?
知道爸爸回来说
我们修的完全不对
TiII Dad came home and toId us
we were doing it aII wrong.
是的。也不告诉我们怎么做才对，
Yeah. Didn't show us
how to do it right,
光叫我们傻瓜、臭屁股，
然后自己做了
just caIIed us stupid, stinking humps
and did it himseIf.
这就是为什么当你生气
我不是这最能干的人，
That's why when you get mad that I'm not
the handiest guy around here,
你知道，这让我感慨万千
you know, it brings up
a Iot of stuff.
真替你难过
I'm sorry.
这么说跟你人懒
So it has nothing to do
with you being Iazy
并且只知道
看电视没关系？
and watching TV
aII the time?
我是在遮盖伤口
That's how
I cover the hurt.
- 嗨，玛丽
- 哈喽，亲爱的
- Hi, Marie.
- HeIIo, dear.
你好呀，吗。
嗷！
Hiya, Ma.
Ow!
- 你干什么？！
- 你们就是
- What are you doing?!
- This is how
- 这么照看你爸的？！
- 我做什么了？！
you watch out for your father?
- What did I do?!
- 你们让他到处搬梯子！
- 他没有搬梯子
- You made him carry Iadders around!
- He didn't carry Iadders.
- 那他怎么扭了背？
- 什么？！
- Then how did he wrench his back?
- What?!
他扛梯子的时候扭了背
He wrenched his back
carrying Iadders.
现在他躺在我的沙发上叫汤
Now he's Iying on my couch
demanding soup.
别告诉他我跟你们说了
And don't teII him
I toId you about this.
他不想让我
闹得沸沸扬扬
He didn't want me
to make a big deaI out of it.
- 那你怎么来了？
- 我不听他的
- So why are you over here?
- I don't Iisten to him.
他的背没事，妈。
我让他回去的
His back is fine, Ma.
I sent him home.
- 我不明白
- 他老讨人嫌，
- I don't understand.
- He was being a big jerk,
所以我炒了他
so I fired him.
什么意思你炒了他？
What do you mean
you fired him?
你炒了你父亲？
You fired your father?
不得已而为之，妈
Had to be done, Ma.
你怎么能那么对他？！
How couId you
do that to him?!
什么意思他？
那他又是怎么对我们的？
What do you mean him?
What about what he does to us?
咱们说的不是这个！
哦……
We're not taIking
about that! Oh...
我真是――哦天
I so-- oh God.
好吧……
AII right...
你爸有件事你们不知道
there's something about your father
you don't know.
他穿你的东西？
He wears your things?
什么，玛丽？
What is it, Marie?
你爸从没从帕尔克
会计事务所退休
Your father never retired
from PeIk Accounting.
你说什么？
What are you
taIking about?
如果他没退休，
那他干嘛
If he's not retired,
why does he
上药店买裤子
（算到医疗保险里）？
buy his pants
at the pharmacy?
他告诉我他退休了，
He toId me he retired,
可我发现了事实
but I found out the truth.
他们解雇了他
They fired him.
什么？
What?
- 为什么？
- Why?
还要我告诉你？
I have to teII you?
你为什么解雇他？
Why did you fire him?
你爸相信他的做事方法
是唯一的方法
Your father beIieves that his way
of doing things is the onIy way.
而过了25年后，
这让人不舒服了
And after 25 years,
it starts to get on peopIe's nerves.
这么说弗兰克从没告诉你
他被解雇了？
So Frank never toId you
he was fired?
他怎么能？
How couId he?
你不明白，黛比拉
You don't understand, Debra.
我们那辈人，
In my generation,
男人工作，并且工作代表了
他是什么
the men had their jobs
and that's who they were.
哦，让那个小个艾文・帕尔克解雇
Oh, it must have been
so humiIiating for Frank
对弗兰克一定是极大的羞辱
to have that IittIe AIvin PeIk
fire him from his job.
而现在你们俩儿子
对他作了同样的事！
And now you boys just did
the same thing to him!
是雷蒙德
It was Raymond.
嘿――不
Hey-- no.
行了，看。
这不一样，好吗？
Come on, Iook. This isn't
the same thing, okay?
这不是他的职业，
这是我的房子
This wasn't his career,
this was my house.
- 他还有什么？！
- 你的房子
- What eIse does he have?!
- Your house.
那个他刷过了！
He did that aIready!
看，妈，我想你反应过度了，
好吗？不是什么大不了的！
Look, Ma, I think you're overreacting,
okay? This wasn't that big of deaI!
足够大到让他跟我
It was a big enough deaI
for him to make up a story
编扭到背的故事
to me about hurting his back.
你是他儿子。你认为
这会让他有什么感受？
You're his son. How do you think
that made him feeI?
- 我希望你高兴了，雷蒙德
- 哦……闭嘴！
- I hope you're happy, Raymond.
- Oh... shut up!
我为什么要担心他的感受？
And why shouId I worry
about his feeIings?
他从不关心其他任何人
He doesn't care
about anybody eIse's.
你认为他不关心你？
You don't think
he cares about you?
他是你父亲。他只是不擅长――
He's your father.
He just isn't good at--
生活在人类中间
Living among humans.
你知道，我想你是唯一
觉得自己有意思的人
You know, I think you're the onIy one
who thinks you're funny.
这话没错
Amen to that.
- 来，来。去那边――
- 不不不，妈
- Come on, come on. Go over there--
- No no no, Ma.
看，我遗憾他的一辈子，好吗？
Look, I'm sorry
about his whoIe Iife, okay?
可他在这完全错了
But he was
compIeteIy wrong here.
他想把我的房子刷成黄的！
He wanted to paint
my house yeIIow!
- 黄色？
- 是的，你能相信吗？
- YeIIow?
- Yeah, you beIieve that?
喔
Wow.
实际上，黄色也不错
ActuaIIy, yeIIow wouId
be kind of nice.
- 什么？
- 唔，我喜欢黄色
- What?
- WeII, I Iike yeIIow.
看，你说的山提利蕾丝
Look, you said
ChantiIIy Lace.
我听到你说的
山提利蕾丝！
I heard you say
ChantiIIy Lace!
我为你的山提利蕾丝抗争，
I fought for your damn
ChantiIIy Lace,
而你现在又说黄色？！
and now you're
saying yeIIow?!
你是谁啊？！
Who are you?!
怎么了？我只是从没想到黄色
What? YeIIow just never
occurred to me.
可是，你知道，
事实上那看着阳光
But, you know,
it's actuaIIy kind of sunny.
你听到了，好吗？
这就是婚姻
You hear this, okay?
This is marriage.
这就是你想要的？
这就是你没了活不了的？
This is what you want?
This is what you can't Iive without?
让位吧
Step aside.
雷蒙德，去和你爸谈谈
Raymond, go taIk
to your father.
- 不不！
- 你知道，你应该的
- No no!
- You know, you shouId.
哦，对不起。
谁在说话？
Oh, excuse me.
Who's speaking?
白的黛比拉
还是黄的黛比拉？
Is that white Debra
or yeIIow Debra?
你知道，你真的应该。
我知道你爸有时的确讨厌
You know, you reaIIy shouId. I know your
father can be a reaI jerk sometimes.
是的，这点没人能反对
Right, no one
is arguing that.
他欺负人，他倔脾气，
He's a buIIy, he's obstinate
而且他不天天洗澡
and he doesn't
bathe every day.
可是我知道这个人，
而且我知道他需要一样东西
But I know that man
and I know he needs one thing.
他需要被人需要
He needs to be needed.
你看着办吧
Do with that what you wiII.
他是你父亲
He's your father.
- 嘿
- Hey.
听着
Listen.
之前的事对不起
I'm sorry about before.
好了，那么……
Okay, so...
回那边
come back over
咱们刷黄的。
黄的没事。我说服了黛比拉
and we'II do it yeIIow.
YeIIow's okay. I taIked Debra into it.
好吗？
Okay?
不
No.
什么意思不？
What do you mean no?
我的意思是，我没兴趣
I mean
I'm not interested.
我现在忙着呢
I'm kind of busy
right now.
哦……
Oh...
是，我看到你的汤了
right, I see you got soup.
还有拼图
And a puzzIe.
唔，不是非得现在。
你想什么时候都可以
WeII, it doesn't have to be right now.
Whenever you feeI Iike it.
什么，你拿锅吃
就因为不想洗个碗
What, you're eating out of a pot
'cause you don't Iike to cIean a bowI?
不，这样更好
No, it's better this way.
哦
Oh.
嘿，眼力不错
Hey, that's a keen eye
you got there.
“石墙杰克森将军之死”
''The Death of GeneraI
StonewaII Jackson''.
你喜欢这个？
You Iike this one?
非常有意思的历史人物
Very interesting figure
in history.
被认为是联盟军队（南军）
最好的将军
Considered the Confederacy's
finest generaI.
被自己人打死
Shot by one
of his own men.
好吧，你有完没完？
AII right, wiII you stop?
天，真不相信
我还请你回去
God, I can't beIieve
I invited you back.
我甚至不相信跟你道歉
I can't beIieve
I apoIogized to you even.
唔，你应该向我道歉，
我是对的！
WeII you shouId apoIogize
to me, I was right!
你怎么对了？
你怎么对了？！
How are you right?
How are you right?!
那是我的房子
而你想刷成黄的！这是怎么对法？
It's my house and you wanted
to paint it yeIIow! How is that right?
因为黄的不显脏！
Because yeIIow
covers better!
不会那么快褪色！
It won't fade as fast!
而且你两边的房子都是白的！
And you got white houses
on either side of you!
这让你的房子看着出彩些！
It makes your house
pop a IittIe!
配你的装修
和你家的狗屁小雏菊！
And it goes with your trim and
the frigging IittIe daisies you got!
唔，你干嘛不直说？
WeII, why didn't you
just say that?
- 我不应该非得说出来！
- 什么？
- I shouIdn't have to say it!
- What?
因为如果我说了黄色，
那就应该对你够好了！
Because if I say it's yeIIow,
that shouId be good enough for you!
我不应该什么都得解释！
I shouIdn't have
to expIain everything!
我是对的！
I'm right!
好吧，你是对的，
可并不总是对错的问题
Okay, you're right,
but it's not aIways about being right.
是，当然是！
对的才是唯一重要的
Yes, it is!
Being right is aII that matters.
别的都是狗屁
Everything eIse is crap!
“哦，你得考虑别人的感受”
''Oh, you have to consider
peopIe's feeIings.''
“哦，要是他们
不喜欢你怎么办？”
''Oh, what if they
don't Iike you?''
他们应该喜欢我，
因为我做得对！
They shouId Iike me
because I did the job right!
是，如果你在灯塔工作
这绝对有道理！
Yeah, that makes perfect sense
if you work in a Iighthouse!
没错。
只要不是和人在一起！
ExactIy. I'd be fine
if it weren't for peopIe!
哦，都是那些该死的人！
唔，你忘了一件事――
Oh, it's those damn peopIe!
WeII, you're forgetting one thing--
我和罗伯特也是人！
me and Robert
are peopIe too!
怎么，你们俩要自己刷了？
So what, are the two of you going
to paint the house now by yourseIves?
是的
Yeah.
如果你想让我帮你，
我会帮你的
If you want me to heIp you,
I'II heIp you.
好吧
Okay.
不过你要是叫我帮忙，
But if you're
asking for my heIp,
咱们就得照我的做，
因为那是对的
we got to do it my way,
because it's the right way.
好吧
AII right.
- 用黄的
- 我说了用黄的
- With the yeIIow.
- I said with the yeIIow.
并且没人告诉我怎么做
And nobody teIIs me
what to do.
得我说了算，
I get to be in charge,
我是老板，怎么样？
I get to be the boss,
aII right?
好吧，爸，你是老板
AII right, Dad,
you're the boss.
- 我是老板？
- 是的
- I'm the boss?
- Yes.
很好。
你被解雇了
Good.
You're fired.
为什么罗伯特可以用电动刷？
How come Robert gets to use
the power painter?
你知道，我也想用电动刷
You know, I want to use
the power painter too.
学会拿刷子先
Learn how to handIe
the brush first.
我知道怎么拿刷子
I know how
to handIe a brush.
你在质疑我？
Are you questioning me?
不
No.
长官！
Sir!
马蜂！
Wasp!
这个得再刷一层
That's going to need
another coat.
jojoba
yettoreturn@hotmail.com